# Yuriaski Leyva Clemente



yuriaskileyva@gmail.com



+48 534456325



linkedin.com/in/yuriasky



https://yugui.design

### Summary

Talented Product Designer with 8 years of experience and track record of optimizing User Experience (UX) and Design Systems via simple navigation and engaging content. Proficient at combining creative and usability viewpoints, resulting in world-class Web and mobile applications. Experienced in boosting user engagement for well-known companies. Recognized for managing complex projects from ideation to completion.

## **Experience**



### Product Designer

cuban.engineer

Sep 2018 - Present (3 years 8 months +)

Served as a Product Designer for one of the biggest software houses in Cuba.

- Alldone (https://alldone.app/): A gamified and modern task management app.
- Liaised with the client to determine requirements and reach the desired product.
- · Oversaw all aspects of Product Management, including managing a team of four developers.
- Created and maintained the design system in Figma.
- · Cally: Digital calendar creation:
- Automated planning and scheduling by digitally developing personalized calendars and delivered to clients in collaboration with two developers.
- Successfully delivered project on time while meeting all requirements by creating necessary user interfaces.
- Cuban.Engineer (https://cuban.engineer): A platform dedicated to recruit the best talented Cuban
- Built more structured and user-friendly Web app by improving whole app based on the results of UX and UI research.

#### User Experience Designer

Kaiko Systems

Dec 2020 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

Acted as UX/UI Designer for a Germany based company that leverages manual operations to generate real time insights for maritime shipping companies.

- Kaiko Systems (https://www.kaikosystems.com/):
- Improved information architecture and user flows of two apps, resulting in enhancement of data gathering and storage.
- Developed a Design System in order to update the applications and add new features, which resulted in the development team adding more functionality in less time and with fewer rollbacks, while also making the apps more appealing and professional.
- Secured more clients due to exceptional performance in this project.

#### Product Designer

Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas

Jan 2016 - Sep 2018 (2 years 9 months)

Served as a member of great development teams and undertook challenging projects as a Product Designer.

- Apklis (https://www.apklis.cu/): Official Cuban Android Apps Store, one of the biggest projects in Cuba.
- Directed the whole project from conception to completion, including brand design by serving as a team lead.
- Performed User research, UX, UI, Interaction Design, animations, and high fidelity wireframes with clickable prototypes.
- Successfully upgraded two apps, one web-based and one native Android, via collaboration with a development team comprised of four developers.
- Achieved 8,265,269 downloads.
- Picta (https://www.picta.cu/): Official Video Streaming Service of Cuba, one of the biggest projects in Cuba.
- Headed the entire project as the lead product designer and worked on Brand Design, User Research, UX, UI, animations, and the high fidelity wireframes with clickable prototypes.
- Achieved 1,03l, 216 downloads.
- · Riegolandia:
- Developed and executed game application similar to the Goose game with seamless functionality.
- · Completed the project using Unity and a design that blends 2D and 3D elements in collaboration with a developer and a 3D designer, as well as interface design and 2D illustrations.

# UX/UI Designer

Frelance worker

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016 (1 year 1 month)

- How to towing: Developed cross-platform application using Xamarin as a UI Designer.
- Baby Up: Delivered engaging and user-friendly mobile application to manage school operations.
- Saz5: Established an online store with a wide range of categories by creating original vector images to illustrate each category of the store and optimize for use on the web as an Illustrator.
- Lávame: Launched a web application to manage laundries and facilitate finding and use.

# Software Developer

Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas

Sep 2014 - Sep 2015 (1 year 1 month)

 Cuban Neuronavigator: Significantly contributed to development of a neuro-navigator (Cuban Neuronavigator) prototype to assist neurosurgeons and psychiatrists.

#### **Education**



#### Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Computer Science

Sep 2009 - Sep 2015

This university is the biggest in Cuba focused only on computing. Here I got my degree, core values and knowledge to thrive in my career as a Product Designer.

#### Skills

User Experience (UX) • User Interface Design • Project Management • Sketching • Wireframing • Rapid Prototyping • Requirements Analysis • Interaction Design • 2D Animation • Motion Graphics